片名：《火線反擊》
布魯克林，紐約，一小時前
把她帶過來！輕點，她只是個孩子！
好吧，我大可以殺了她
你在騙我
You're lying to me.
沒有！我不知道你在說什麼
I'm not.
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你想要什麼，我發誓
I don't know what you want from me.
I swear I don't.
我有三個孩子
I have three children.
作為父親，首先要學會的
The first thing you have to learn
as a father is to know
就是知道你的孩子何時在欺騙你
when your children are lying to you.
你在欺騙我，如果你不說真話
You're lying to me,
and if you don't stop,
我就要用你們那些有名的手段
I'm going to use one of those tortures
your people are so famous for
來折磨你弱小的身體，直到你告訴我一切
on your little body
until you tell me what I want to know.
最後一次，告訴我那些數字
For the last time,
give me the numbers.
204,35倍，是另外一種算法，加起來是350
南京，中國，一年前
如果用另外一種算法，加起來是365
只有一個算法是對的
（兩人都做錯了，定義域是X|X≠-2，
嘴上說的和黑板上的也牛頭不對馬嘴）
蘇先生，我沒有不尊重你的意思
但是你的算法是錯的
梅
我們要把你轉去另一個學校
可是我的朋友都在這兒，而且我的媽媽...
梅，你太聰明了，你是個天才
你該上一個特殊的學校
你可以找新朋友的
別難過，梅，我們永遠都是你的朋友，聽說北京的小孩人都很好的
你在那兒會過得很開心的
我根本就不喜歡數學
我喜歡我現在的朋友，我不想要交新的朋友，我不喜歡數學
你來做數學，我們給你寫信，
我們每個星期都給你往北京寫封信
你發誓？
當然，你想讓我們失去一個有名的朋友嗎？
不，梅，我們永遠都是你的...
梅！
Mei!
新澤西聯航中心球館
你怎麼還敢來這？
How dare you come here!
You have no right!
- 媽媽！別打了！住手！
- 你沒資格待在這裡！沒資格！
- Ma, enough! Stop!
- You've no right to be here. No right!
你應該被關在監獄裡！監獄裡！
You should be in jail!
滾出去！你給我滾出去！
You get out of here!
You get out of here.
- 對不起
- 我要殺掉你！我會殺掉你的！
- I'm sorry.
- I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
你個廢物！那孩子不應該出現在擂台上！
Piece of garbage. The kid
should never been in there with me.
路克，別這樣！你瘋了嗎？
Luke, come on. What, are you crazy, man?
- 走開！
- 給我走開！
- Get off.
- Get off, now!
我從來都不喜歡你，路克
I never liked you, Luke.
你比擂台上90%的人都厲害
You're a betterfighter than 90%
of the guys you go in the cage with,
但你卻任人蹂躪
but you just let 'em pound on you
like you're a side of beef.
你幾乎輸給過擂台上的每一個笨蛋
You already lost to every chump
in the circuit.
但是昨晚
But last night, of all nights,
你應該在第二輪輸掉的，你個混蛋
you're supposed to go down
in the second, you son of a bitch.
- 僅僅一拳！
- 退後！
- Once.
- Back off.
我就打了他一拳！你從哪裡找到他的，操場？
I hit him once. Where'd you find him,
the fucking playground?
Youtube，你個混蛋
YouTube, you asshole.
在你把他打暈前，那個孩子還是個網絡紅人
The kid's an internet sensation
until you put him in a coma,
坦白說，我並不關心這個
which frankly
I do not give a shit about.
但是你讓我輸掉了100萬美元
But you cost me a million dollars,
當然這和你讓德切斯基輸掉的比起來就不算什麼了
which is nothing
compared what you cost Docheski.
很好！這個名字耳熟吧？
Yeah. You recognise the name?
他在你身上下了大賭注
He was betting on you big time
to take the dive.
他會把這一切都怪罪到我頭上來的
And he's gonna take it out on me too
因為他知道這件事情是我這白癡搞出來的
'cause he knows I'm the schmuck
that set this whole thing up.
除非我把你的腦袋送給他
Unless I deliver your head
with a down payment.
你知道俄國人是什麼樣子的
You know how the Russians are.
梅
Mei.
這是我的侄女，白玉
認識吧？
她在我朋友的班裡
她說啊，你的腦筋啊很像電腦
我跟你的老師講過了，他也這樣說
你知道了吧
很可愛啊
電腦很討厭，太容易留下痕跡，他們還說...
走開呀，走開！
你學的東西你不會忘的，是不是？
那我到你的家，把你的媽媽殺掉好不好啊！
很好，很好
看來他們說的對了
蘇先生告訴我你小的時候你爸爸已經走掉了
你的媽媽現在很病了
很快你變成一個人，你喜歡孤獨嗎？
放心，我們會好好照顧你的媽媽
張，你的新爸爸
他呢會帶你漂洋過海，不過那邊那裡的人呢很喜歡
找我們的麻煩，所以我要你
幫我們算一算
你打對號碼了，有什麼事就留言吧
You got the right number,
so leave the right message.
聽到後立刻給我回電，安妮，立刻
Call me when you get this, Annie.
I mean right away.
如果你出去了，別回家
If you're out, don't go home.
我不是在嚇唬你，記得趕緊回電話
If I'm scaring you, that's good.
Call me.
安妮？
Annie?
就這樣？
That's it?
我聽說你是個硬漢啊
I heard you were
some kind of a tough guy.
不掙扎下？
No fighting?
就直接跪在地上像只求死的狗一樣？
You're just going to sit on the floor
like a dog who wants to die?
不好意思搞得那麼亂
Sorry it had to be so messy.
這些家伙還在學習中
The boy is still learning.
我雖然不是醫生，但我想她有孩子了
And I'm not a doctor,
but I think she was eating for two.
我們就像查爾斯•曼森家一樣
We're like Charlie Manson family, no?
我父親本想派其他人來的，但我想鍛煉下
My father was going to send
someone else, but I'm making my bones.
你就靠殺害那些沒有還手能力的人來鍛煉
You make your bones by killing someone
who can hurt you back.
那會是誰呢？你？
And who would that be? You?
好吧，當然是你
Well, why not?
你剛殺了你老婆
You just killed your wife.
我沒殺她，是你殺的！
I didn't kill her. You did.
但是，你想傷害我？很好
Look, you want to hurt me? Good.
我倒想看看你能做些什麼
I want to see you try.
殺了我吧
Get it over with.
殺了你？你讓我父親輸錢，讓我的家族難堪
Over? You cost my father money,
made my family look bad.
現在我們想把你作為一個特例對待
Now we're going to make
an extra special example out of you.
我們查過你的檔案，沒有什麼有趣的東西
So, we looked into your records.
Not much to find.
為城市的衛生系統工作
Work for city,
garbage collection, sanitation.
收益不錯，但是缺乏魅力，不是麼？
Good benefits but no glamour, eh?
父母雙亡，沒有兄弟姐妹
Father and mother dead,
no brothers or sisters,
這真是糟糕
which is too bad,
我本想把他們都干掉的
because I would like
to take them from you too.
但是你愛你的老婆，我們知道這點
But you love your wife.
We know that.
那麼，這樣子說定了：
So here's the deal.
你可以走了，不過我們會盯著你的
You're free to go,
but we will have eyes on you.
不是一直，但是我們會在你最不希望出現的時候出現
Not always, but when
you least expect it, we'll be there.
任何一個你想結交的人，甚至是交談過的
Anyone you try to make friends with
or even talk to,
反正是有過任何交集的人
other than ordering a hot dog
or something,
都會像你老婆一樣因你而死
will die, like your wife,
because of you.
當然你可以隨時結束這一切！跳橋
Of course, you can always end it,
jump off a bridge,
臥軌
throw yourself in front of a train,
將你的不朽的靈魂送去地獄，如果你相信這些狗屁
damn your eternal soul to hell,
if you believe in that kind of bullshit.
就我個人來說，我不相信
Personally, I don't.
所以，如果我是你，我寧願去自殺
So I'd go for it if I were you.
但是我不是你
But I am not you.
感謝上帝
Thank God.
所以做你想做的事吧
So do what you want.
如果你明天還在這，我們會殺掉房東
If you're still here tomorrow,
we're going to kill the landlady.
- 她叫什麼名字？
- 特巴洛斯基
- What was her name?
- Tobolovsky.
特巴洛斯基夫人
Mrs Tobolovsky.
很好
Nice lady.
收拾一下吧，清潔工
Clean up the mess, garbage man.
好了！她是你女兒，她也是美國公民
All right, she's your daughter
and she's an American citizen.
我不會打聽你們的關系，這是你們的事
I ain't gonna ask what the deal is
with her. That's your business.
不過我想說的是，找關系是很困難的
But I'm gonna tell you,
pulling strings is hard work,
困難的工作一般不會免費
and hard work don't come free.
開個價吧，沃夫隊長
Your price, Captain Wolf?
中國城轄區多交20%
Chinatown precinct take goes up 20%.
布朗克斯，布魯克林每個月各漲10%
Bronx 121st, Brooklyn divisions,
each go up by 10%, monthly.
這個價格對於一個小女孩的護照和文書工作來說太過分了
That's a steep price for a passport
and some papers for a little girl.
現在的日子都不好過啊
Things are tough all over.
中國城加10%
Chinatown gets upped 10%.
布朗克斯和布魯克林不變
Bronx and Brooklyn will settle
for the current rate
然後我們在感受到壓力的時候
and the fact
that we won't start shooting
不會隨意射殺街上的警察和警察家屬
cops and their families in the streets
like dogs at the first sign of pressure.
現在的日子都不好過啊
Things are tough all over.
嘿，朋友，我見過你，我看過你在新澤西的拳擊
Hey, man, I know you.
I saw yourfight in Jersey.
實在是太棒了，你輕松干掉了那家伙
It was really good.
You knocked that guy out.
- 不是的
- 我有好東西，兄弟
- No.
- That was some good shit, man.
很棒的格斗
Great fight.
衛路的店，這個禮拜是兩萬六千，上個禮拜是二十六
侯進每個禮拜是正好一萬五千
他在博易街的店
中國城，紐約，一年後
五月份在丟錢，但是七月八月份他就賺回來了
邵成，上個禮拜是42，這個禮拜是42.5
每個月盈利增長7%
莫特區整個盈利總共上升了72535
我們從梁先生那裡拿了5%
他們都每個禮拜盈利6千到8千
賭場呢？
The casino?
上個禮拜是八十萬，這個禮拜也是八十萬
80萬整？
Exactly 800,000?
大約80萬
It's almost 800.
我不是問你是不是大概80萬
I'm not asking you if it's almost 800.
我要准確數字
I want the exact number.
78萬5370美元
$785,370.
- 再上一周呢？
- 在虧錢
- And the week before?
- It's losing money.
停！
不要打了，拜托，不要打了
今晚，你們會有一個新的場上工頭
如果錢又少了，那就不知道誰會走！
今天晚上他請
肯定不是我請
肯定你啊，這麼多錢
他贏了這麼多錢
- 怎麼？
- 為什麼？
- What?
- Why?
因為他損害了生意，生意是件很嚴肅的事情
Because he was hurting business,
and business is a serious matter.
我懂生意
I understand business.
但是既然要殺他，為什麼還要打他？
But why beat him
if you were going to kill him anyway?
看來你還是不懂這個生意，不說了
吃你的飯吧
靠，靠！
Fuck you. Fuck you!
- 你不能進來
- 我只想要些吃的！
- You can't come in the shelter.
- Just trying to get something to eat!
趕緊睡覺！5分鍾後熄燈
Wrap it up. Lights out in five.
趕緊睡覺
Wrap it up.
快點
Come on, guys.
好鞋子
Nice kicks.
最好早上它們還在，不然你就得用耳朵穿上它們了
They'd better be here in the morning
or you'll be wearing them on your ears,
因為我會把你的腳給扭下來
'cause I'll chew yourfeet off
at the goddamn ankles.
我真的想要雙新點的鞋子，我會為你做任何事情
I could really use some new shoes, man.
I'll do whatever you want, you know?
任何能幫你熬過晚上的事情
Whatever gets you through the night.
- 我不能...
- 閉嘴，閉嘴！
- I just... I can't take another...
- Shut up. Shut up.
閉嘴，拿走吧，我還有舊鞋子
Shut up and take them.
I've still got my old ones.
好好照顧你的腳
Go and get those feet looked at.
都爛掉了
Gangrene's setting in.
我會的，謝謝你，朋友
I will. Thank you, man.
上帝保佑你，兄弟，上帝保佑你
Jesus loves you, brother.
Jesus loves you.
熄燈了，明早七點會叫醒你們的
Lights out. Wake-up call's 7am.
熄燈
Lights out.
噓
Shh.
梅，我有個壞消息
Mei, I have sad news.
我聽到他們在談論…你媽媽走了
I heard them talking and...
your mother is gone.
她兩周前在醫院去世了
She died two weeks ago in the hospital.
他們不會告訴你的
They werert going to tell you,
但是我告訴你，這樣子你可以為她的靈魂祈禱
but I'm telling you
so that you can pray
讓她找到去天堂的路
for her soul to find its way to heaven.
別告訴他們，如果他們發現我告訴你…
Please don't say anything.
If they find out I told you...
我會保密的，謝謝
I won't say anything. Thank you
所有人起床！9點前離開這裡
Everybody up.
Shelter needs to be cleared by 9am.
在3：30前辦好今晚的床鋪預定
Bed reservations for tonight
need to be made by 3:30.
帶走所有個人物品
Please remove
all your personal belongings.
所有人起床！走了！
Everybody up. Come on, let's go.
帶好個人物品，你們知道規矩的
Take your belongings with you.
You know the drill.
那麼，告訴我們發生了什麼
So you wanna tell us what happened?
有人喜歡那鞋子
Someone liked his shoes.
搞笑的家伙！你認為這是個玩笑？
Funny guy. You think this is a joke?
你們知道的，你們這幫保安有多糟糕
You know, you guys
are a hell of a crack security squad.
你做的很對，你本來可以說些什麼的
You were right here.
You could have said something.
但是你喝醉酒忙著睡覺，是不是？
But you were too busy
sleeping off this contraband, right?
你如果再來這個避難所
Come into this shelter again
我就把你踹到大街上去
and I'm gonna run your raggedy ass
back out into the street.
梅，到你房間去記住這些數字
我已經記住了
這些數字很重要
為了你媽，你要認真一點，知道嗎？
你真的記住了？
我可以給你重復一遍，但是又長又無聊
你看，還沒到一年呢，她已經自信的很了
如果，她說她可以背出密碼，她就能背出
我保證
好了好了
我們要交給你一個很重要的工作
嘿！走路不看路的？
Hey! Watch where you're going, man.
要不要給你點顏色瞧瞧？
You could get your ass
kicked for that, OK? Huh?
4塊5毛5
4.55.
你沒錢就得出去
If you got no money,
you gotta get out of line.
我有錢
I got money.
他沒有錢，看看他那樣子
He doesn't have any money.
Look at him.
先生，我告訴過你，如果你沒錢，你得離開，懂嗎？
Mister, I told you, if you don't
have money, you have to leave, OK?
讓開，還有人在等呢
You gotta get out of line.
People are waiting.
走開，兄弟，讓開
Come on, buddy. You gotta go.
- 這家伙惹麻煩了嗎？
- 他瘋了，長官
- This guy giving you trouble?
- He's crazy, Officer.
- 把他帶出去，好嗎？
- 好的，過來，我們走
- Get him out of here, OK?
- All right, come on, let's go.
嘿，你！過來，我們走！出去！到街上去！
Hey, you, come on. Let's go.
Out. On the street.
哥們，如果你想當小丑，去馬戲團
Let's go, funny boy. You wanna be
a clown, go join the circus.
別在我轄區鬧事，聽懂了嗎？
我不想在這附近再見到你，嘿！
Not in my precinct, you hear me?
I don't wanna see you around here. Hey.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
看看我抓到了誰
Look what the cat dragged in.
不可思議
Unbelievable.
- 看著他
- 看著他？
- Look at him.
- Look at him?
不去聞聞？
How about the smell?
我打電話叫大家過來
Think I'll call the boys.
梅，這是你的指令
張會帶你見一個人，那個人會給你一個新的數字
記住那個數字
然後呢張會帶你去一個地方，你會得到最後的指令
想我們嗎，伙計？
You miss us, partner?
歡迎回來
Welcome back to the force.
梅…
Mei...
你學的很快
如果干的好，你會跟著韓叔前途無量
對不起，我不能讓他們抓到你
I'm sorry. I can't let them have you.
梅！回來這裡！
Mei! Get back here!
- 日子過的怎麼樣，路克？
- 悲劇，不過正在變好
- How's your day been, Luke?
- Started lousy. But it's looking up.
路克•萊特，以前紐約最佳警察
Luke Wright, the Big Apple's hardest cop
once upon a time.
什麼都敢試，但你知道你真正的才能嗎？
You always could take a shot.
But you know what your real talent is?
你是個牽線人！我是說，誰會想到
You're a uniter. I mean, who'd
have thought that us and the Russkies
我們會和俄國佬拴在一起？
would ever be on the same page
about anything?
不是我！很高興見到你，混蛋！
Not me. Nice to see you, rat.
自從你出賣我們，我就一直想這麼做了
Been wanting to do this ever since the
day you opened your big fucking mouth!
當我們聽說德切斯基如何對付你時，我笑慘了
When we heard what Docheski did to you,
I mean, I had to laugh.
對於安妮我們很抱歉
I mean, we felt bad for Annie ar all.
她知道她和誰在一起
Them's the breaks.
She knew who she was with.
街上有流言說你回來的時候
Word come up from the street
you were back,
我們甚至不敢相信
we couldn't believe our fucking ears.
你為什麼回來？為什麼不遠走高飛？
Why would you come back? Why wouldn't
you disappear somewhere far way, huh?
比如說月球
Like the moon.
我想家了
I missed home.
你曾是我們一員，路克，我們曾是一個團隊，一個家庭
You were one of us, Luke.
We were a team. We were family.
- 然後你扔下了我們
- 我們曾經有多風光，混蛋
- Then you threw us under the bus.
- We were kings, you son of a bitch!
現在，我們只是一群可憐蟲
Now we're bunch of goddamn serfs.
嘿，嘿，冷靜，伯努瓦
Hey, hey, easy, Benoit, huh?
當你回來的時候，我們以為你想尋死
When you came back,
we figured you wanted to die.
我們還開了個盤口賭你怎麼死，你知道的
We got a pool going on when
you're gonna end it and how, you know,
公交，火車…
bus, train...
我賭“找警察自殺”
I got my money on suicide by cop.
來吧，拿好了
Come on, take it.
來一槍，來吧
Take a shot. Come on.
安妮在等著你
Annie's waiting for you.
問題是，你真的認為她想再見到你嗎
Question is, do you really think
she wants to see you again?
嗯？
Hmm?
其實我真正的才能是讓別人輸錢
Actually, my real talent
is costing other people money.
你早就應該知道的，拉斯基
You ought to know that, Lesky.
你會輸錢的，除非你朝我背後開槍
You're gonna lose that bet.
Unless you wanna shoot me in the back.
不過對你來說也不是第一次了
Wouldrt be your first time.
你為什麼不了結這一切？
Why don't you just end it?
你在等什麼？
What are you waiting for?
身邊的人死去更多？
More people around you to die?
你到底在等什麼？
What are you waiting for?
最後一次，告訴我那些數字
For the last time,
give me the numbers.
你是個勇敢的女孩，而且很聰明
You're a very brave girl, and clever.
但你知道我們如何知道你的本事嗎？
But do you know how we knew exactly
what you can do,
你要在什麼時間去什麼地方
where you're going to be and when?
- 有人告訴你了
- 對
- Someone told you.
- That's right.
猜猜是誰？
Can you guess who?
你的朋友，告訴你關於你可憐母親事情的人
Yourfriend, the one who told you
about your poor mother
將你從家裡帶走的流氓可不會告訴你那些
when the scum
who took you from home would not.
她在幫我們做事
She's working for us with a smile.
玲
Ling.
梅，我跟他們講他們想知道的事情
他們給了我一把一把的錢
沒事，你要是這麼做他們也會幫助你的
你真是個笨女人
講英語
In English.
你不知道生意
你給了他們想要的東西，現在他們要殺了你
我說了，講英語！
I said speak in English.
怎麼樣？
Well?
她不肯告訴我任何事
She won't tell me anything.
我的父親很有耐心
My father is a patient man.
我沒有
I am not.
告訴他他想知道的一切
Tell him what he wants to know.
不然我就…
Or I'II...
紐約警察！開門！
NYPD! Open the door!
- 搞什麼？
- 我們是警察
- What the hell?
- This is the police.
我們接到報警說擾民
We got reports of a disturbance.
你可以選擇配合或者硬來
Look, you can make this easy
or you can make it hard.
開門，不然我們就要砸門了
Open the door or we come in by force.
放屁
Bullshit, blue.
你敢進來就別想活著出去，我以母親之名發誓
You come in here, you go out feet first,
I swear on my mother.
他們在裡面，隊長
Yeah, they're in there, Captain.
他們一點都不配合，你最好在事情失控前過來
They're not cooperating. You better
get down here before things go to hell.
不行，這事鬧大了
Negative, negative. This is big.
我馬上回警局指揮，我們再聯系
I'm going back to the station to monitor
the city. I'll get back to you.
好了，我們找到她了，你知道我想要什麼
All right, we got 'em pinned down.
You know what I want.
我們有言在先，抓到女孩，可以就活捉，不行就干掉
We have a deal. Get the girl,
alive if you can, dead if you can't.
我們進去的話，布魯克林上升10%，這是新的約定
We go in, Brooklyrs take
goes up by 10%. That's the new deal.
等等，我有個電話要接
Hold on, I got an incoming call.
- 嘿，埃米爾，怎麼了？
- 把你的人弄走，混蛋
- Emile, what's up?
- Take your men off, Wolf.
不管中國人給你什麼，我都加5%
Whatever the Chinese offered to you,
I'll up it by 5%.
把她帶回來
Get her back here.
好了，關
All right, Quan,
俄羅斯人提供我布魯克林7%
I got the Russians
offering to up Brooklyrs take by 7%,
布朗克斯也一樣，所以我不知道該怎麼和你說
Bronx the same.
So I don't know what to tell you.
我的手下，他們寧願去打仗
My guys are willing
to go to war over this.
卡在我們和俄國人之間
You're gonna be stuck between us
and the Russians like Hitler,
就像希特勒雙線作戰，所以你要想清楚
fighting on two fronts,
so you better think hard about this one.
10%，兩個區域，最終提案
10%, both precincts, final offer.
嘿，麥克，這兩幫家伙都願意
Hey, Mac. Both these bastards
are willing to pay a stiff price
為這小姑娘出大價錢
for this little Chink girl.
- 不管她有什麼，我想要
- 那我們的計劃是？
- Whatever she's got, I want it.
- So what's our play?
我讓俄國人放下武器，你們進去
I get the Russians
to drop their guard, you go in.
如果她中槍了
She catches a bullet,
I want you to take out every last one
你給我把布爾什維克的都干掉
of those Bolshevik scumbags.
好的，埃米爾，你的提議不錯
All right, Emile, your offer's good.
我會讓我的人撤走的，只因為我更喜歡你！
I'm gonna call my guys off,
but only 'cause I like you better.
狗屁！你是個貪婪的混蛋，沃夫
Bullshit. You're a greedy bastard, Wolf.
你的嗅覺很靈敏，你想把一切占為己有
You got the scent of something big
and now you want it all for yourself.
不過我想在你派手下進來前告訴你些事情
But I have to tell you something before
you send your men in guns blazing.
- 她不見了
- 你指什麼，她不見了？
- She's gone.
- What do you mean, she's gone?
她逃走了，你的人堵在外面我沒法追她
I mean she escaped, and with
all your men out there, I can't follow.
我提議在找到她之前我們停戰
I offeryou a truce until we find her.
我發誓，如果中國人先找到她
Trust me, the Chinese find her first,
你會為此後悔一輩子的
that will be a thing you regret
as long as you live.
德切斯基，她到底知道些什麼？
Docheski, what does she have?
我們說定了嗎，沃夫隊長？
Do we have a truce, Captain Wolf?
女孩是中國人，11歲
The girl is Chinese, 11 years old.
會說普通話和英語
She speaks Mandarin and English.
照片已經下發
A photo is being disseminated.
找到她後直接帶她去中心大街
You are to find her
and bring her straight to Centre Street.
她在往地鐵去
She's heading for subway.
警察跟我們干上了
是嗎？
你沒有辦法？
你這個不動腦筋的笨蛋,如果你讓警察
或俄國人先找到那個女孩,我就砍了你人頭
我們開打吧
對不起，安妮
Sorry, Annie.
俄國人的手機信號在J大街消失了
Lost my lock
on the Russian cell on Jay Street.
聽起來他們是進了地鐵站
Sounds like they went into
the subway station. Manattan bound.
嘿
Hey.
你？那個清潔工？
You? The garbage collector?
你們的情報太糟糕了
You've got bad information.
我從來不收垃圾
我只丟垃圾
I never collected garbage.
I disposed of it.
別被嚇得失眠了，他應得的
Don't lose sleep. He had it coming.
你還好嗎？
Are you all right?
- 出去！出去！
- 快
- Get out! Get out!
- Move.
沒事了
It's OK.
最後目擊到女孩進了J大街地鐵站，紅色警報
Girl was last seen entering
Jay Street Station. Red alert.
一旦找到，立刻帶她到中央大街的沃夫隊長這
Once found, she needs to be brought
to Captain Wolf at Centre Street.
重復，紅色警報
Repeat, red alert.
嘿，孩子，我們是警察
Whoa. Easy. Easy there, hon.
We're the police.
好了沒事了
Everything's all right.
你叫什麼？孩子
Hey, what's your name, hon?
就是她
This is her.
我不知道，對我來說他們看起來都一樣
I don't know. They all look alike to me.
- 你有那照片嗎？
- 有，讓我看看…
- You got that picture up?
- Yeah, let me see.
該死的紐約
Fucking New York City.
好久沒見到某些人的話
Don't see somebody for years.
你一天會遇到他們兩次
Then you bump into them twice
in the same day.
我不會傷害你的，孩子
Hey, hey, hey. I'm not gonna hurt you.
你到底做了什麼，孩子？
What the hell did you do, kid?
這些追你的都是壞人
You know, those men chasing you are bad.
你能告訴我他們為什麼追你嗎
You wanna tell me why they're after you?
你懂我在說什麼嗎？
You understand me?
你會說英語嗎？
Speak English?
什姆亞金和其他人消失了是什麼意思？
有人把她帶走了
不是警察，他還差點干掉幾個警察
也不是中國人，我不知道他到底是誰
干掉他，活捉女孩，不行就全干掉
走另一邊！都是車！
The other way! Cars go the other way!
你瘋了嗎？
Are you a crazy man?
坐穩了
Hold on.
這樣下去,很多無辜的人會受傷
If this goes on, a lot of
innocent people are gonna get hurt.
你希望那樣子嗎?
You want that?
很好！那就按我說的做
Good. Then do what I say.
你還好嗎？
You OK?
我們走
Let's go.
我不是5歲小孩
I'm not five years old.
那就跟上
Then keep up
- 你們找到後又跟丟了？
- 不，隊長，我們沒有跟丟她
- You had her and you lost her.
- No, Captain, we didn't lose her.
她被搶走了
She was taken by force.
- 俄國人？
- 不是俄國人
- The Russians?
- No, not the Russians.
好吧…
Well...
- 是路克•萊特
- 什麼？
- It was Luke Wright.
- What?
- 沃夫隊長
- 等會，大衛
- Captain Wolf?
- Not now, David.
市長想找你，隊長
The mayor wants you, Captain.
- 把他接到2線
- 不是電話
- Put him through on two.
- He's not on the phone.
他想讓你去大廈…昨天
He wants you at the mansion, yesterday.
給您
There you go.
- 謝謝，伊萬諾夫先生
- 謝謝
- Thank you, Mr Ivanov.
- Thank you.
伊萬諾夫先生？給您，伊萬諾夫先生，1012號房間
Mr Ivanov?
Here you are, Mr Ivanov. Room 1012.
- 10樓
- 謝謝
- Tenth Floor.
- Thank you.
你喜歡高檔酒店？
You like a nice hotel.
我從來沒住過高檔酒店
I've never stayed in a nice hotel.
所以沒人會到這種地方找我們
No one's gonna look for us in one.
她一定在這裡，不過我看不清楚
干擾太多
等一下
等一下！
我找到她了
多想現在洗個澡啊
Would I love a shower right now.
你可以洗的
You could use one.
我大可以讓俄國人把你帶下列車
I could have just let those Russians
grab you on the train.
那你為什麼要救我？
Why did you save me?
我沒救你…是你救了我
I didn't save you. You saved me.
我只是作為回報
I'm paying you back.
我叫路克
My name's Luke.
梅
Mei.
你有父母嗎，梅？
You have parents, Mei?
- 我有父親
- 他叫什麼?
- I have a father.
- What's his name?
張關
Chang Quan.
張關？
Chang Quan?
如果我們是在說同一個人的話
If we're talking about the same guy,
據我所知他根本沒孩子
he didn't have any kids
last time I checked.
這沒道理，他不可能有像你那麼大的孩子
Any made since
wouldn't be a day over three years old.
我是領養的
I'm adopted.
他從老家帶你來這的？
He bring you overfrom back home?
張不像是個做父親的人
Chang isn't the fatherly type.
你為什麼來這，梅？
Why are you here, Mei?
做會計
To count.
你是被張的老板，那個老家伙送來的？他叫什麼？
You were sent over by the old guy,
Chang's boss. What's his name?
沒有電腦，沒有電子資料
Old school.
No computers, no electronic trails.
只有你腦子裡的東西，是嗎？
Just what you have
in your head, right?
- 你知道韓礁嗎？
- 我知道他
- You know Jiao Han?
- I know of him.
他告訴了我一個數字，非常長的一個數字
He told me a number,
a very long number.
我本來要去個地方拿下個數字和指示
I was going someplace where I would get
another number and more instructions,
但是俄國人現身殺了所有人
but the Russian came and shot everyone.
之後警察又出現了，我就逃走了
Then the police came and I ran away.
現在你知道一切了，高興了嗎？
Now you know everything.
Happiness for you?
想回去找韓礁嗎？
You wanna go back to Han Jiao?
我造成了太多麻煩
生意搞砸了
I make too much trouble. Bad business.
事成之後，他會殺掉我，真是如意算盤
After I do what he asks, he kills me.
Good business.
那麼，這組數字是什麼？
So what about this number?
一個又長又無聊的數字，我可以告訴你
It's a long, boring number.
I can tell it to you.
對我來說毫無意義
It wouldn't mean anything to me.
你怎麼知道是一個數字而非一堆獨立數字呢？
How do you know it's one number
and not a bunch of separate numbers?
你是個瘋子，但是倒不蠢
You're a crazy man but not so stupid.
這些數字對你來說有何特別嗎？
Is there anything interesting to you
about these numbers?
- 或許有點
- 為什麼？
- Maybe a few of them.
- Why?
因為他們都是3或者7開頭
Because they have a three or a seven
before them.
所有數字都是隨機的
All the numbers are random,
但當中5個是7開頭的，8個是3開頭的
but five of them has a seven before
and eight of them has a three before.
對於隨機數來說這頻率太高
That's too many times to be random.
這是個密碼
It's a code.
- 還有呢？
- 沒了
- What else?
- Nothing.
那麼，這些3和7是比較有用的
So the three and the seven
are interesting
因為他們隨機出現了太多次？
because they happen too many times
to be random.
因為它們不是數字，是單詞
Because they're not numbers.
They're words.
從左到右或者從右到左
Right left or left right.
老手法了，保險箱的密碼
Old school. Combination to a safe.
在這個酒店裡？
In the hotel?
哪？
Where?
我能查到的就是這些了
怎麼樣?
我們現在在找一個男的，他和一個女孩在一起
他有武器，非常危險，警察局的人說他是…
大概5尺11寸，褐色頭發，30歲左右
About five eleven, brown hair, 30s.
大概幾小時前來的
Probably came in here
less than a few hours ago.
先生，我們不允許透露顧客信息
Sir, we're not allowed
to discuss our guests.
那麼，他確實是客人了？他入住了嗎？
So he's a guest? Did he check in?
對不起，先生，我們不能…
I'm sorry, sir.
We're not at liberty to...
他和一個中國女孩在一起，11歲
He would have been with a Chinese girl,
11 years old.
我是她的父親，我很擔心她
I'm herfather
and I'm very worried about her.
真抱歉，我可以幫你報警
I'm so sorry.
I can call the police for you.
你敢報警我殺了你
Do that and I blow your brains out.
- 現在…
- 別動
- Now...
- Don't move.
他在哪個房間？
...what room is he in?
哪個房間？
What room is he in?
我想…他是在10樓
I think maybe
I put him on the 10th floor.
哪個房間？
Room.
我發誓，他沒有帶著一個小女孩
I swear he didn't have
a little girl with him.
- 房間
- 我需要查一下
- Room.
- I just need to check.
那就快查，或者我給你一槍
Then check quick
or I put a bullet in your brain.
- 快
- 把手舉起來
- Quick.
- Put your hands up.
- 你不會想這麼做的
- 把手舉高讓我看見
- You don't want any part of this.
- Hands up so I can see 'em.
沒人可以離開這酒店
No one leaves the hotel!
快點！
Come on!
1012，他在1012房
1012. He's in room 1012.
我以為你說沒人會到這裡找我們
I thought you said
no one would look for us here.
我把它關掉了，沒人能打進來
I turned it off
so no one could call when I was...
它不需要被開著
It doesn't need to be on.
- 回去！
- 等等！
- Get back!
- Wait!
都給我趴在地上！
Get down on the floor.
所有人回去！
Everybody back!
寫下那些數字
Write down the numbers,
那些3和7開頭的，快！
just the ones with the three
and the seven in front of 'em, quick.
你！過來這裡！趴下！趴下！
You, get over there! Get down! Get down!
我會想辦法帶你去安全的地方
I'll try to get you someplace safe.
如果我們分開了，別說你跟我說過什麼！
We get separated,
don't tell them you told me anything.
- 梅，如果他們試圖嚇唬你…
- 試圖？我已經被嚇到了！
- Mei, if they try to scare you...
- Try? I'm so scared already.
嗯，我也是，記住，撒謊！
Yeah, me to. Remember, lie.
我們快到了
We're almost there.
如果你們看到他們下樓，小心別殺了那個女孩
If you see them downstairs,
try not to kill the girl.
進去
Back inside.
跟上他們！我下樓去斷他們退路！
Follow them!
I'm going back down to cut them off.
警察來了，頂住他們直到我下令撤退！
The cops are here.
Hold them off until I give the word.
別讓他們進來
Do not let them in!
所有人給我趴下，你們走不了了
Everybody stay down!
You ain't going nowhere! Stay!
嘿！你去哪？回去！站住！蹲下！都回去！
Hey, where you going?
Get down! No! Get back down!
- 回去！
- 快！快！
- Get back!
- Move! Move!
起來！所有人起來！
Get up! Everybody up!
我們要離開酒店了，起來！
We're getting out of the hotel. Up!
站起來，不然我就開槍了！站起來！
Up or I start shooting you! Up!
58號轉角，我們發現嫌疑犯
Moving to corner of 58.
We got a suspect.
別動！
Hey, don't move!
Don't move!
走！往那走！
Move! Move! Over there! Go!
到街上去，別停！誰不聽話下場就是這樣！
Into the street and keep moving!
Anyone who doesn't dies like this!
到街上去
Into the street!
重復，別開槍！
Repeat, hold your fire!
那些都是平民！
They're civilians!
嫌犯在人群中，嫌犯在人群中
Suspect is in the crowd.
嘿！給我站住！
Hey, stop right there!
嘿，你干什麼！
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
我的車！做點什麼！他搶了我的車！
That's my car!
Do something, he took my fucking car!
往市中心開，我過一會告訴你地址
Head downtown.
I'll give you an address in a minute.
靠
Shit.
- 嘿，朋友！可以告訴我地址了嗎？
- 等一下
- Hey, buddy, you wanna give me address?
- In a minute. Just hold on.
誰？
你以為是誰？我是皮特,你電話裡沒我號碼嗎？
皮特？警察說在地鐵裡發現你跟...
警方報告有誤
其他人被...
什麼聲音？
抱歉，信號不好
我拿到數字了
什麼？
在她被劫走前，我們從她那拿到數字了
我跟條子玩了幾個小時的捉迷藏
伊哥，把數字記到手機裡
說吧，告訴我數字
你瘋了嗎？數字在一公裡外一張紙上，你在哪？
他可能帶警察來了
我們要清場嗎？
如果有警察，我們最好避開人群
而且需要有利地形
好的，皮特...
現在給你個機會做英雄
曼夢西卡見
快來
我馬上到
他回來了？路克•萊特回到我的城市了？
He's here? Luke Wright is back
in the city, in my city?
他已經回來有一段時間了
He's been back for a while.
- 一段時間？多久？
- 可能一年，這很難說
- A while? What's a while?
- Maybe a year. It's hard to say.
掛掉電話！
Turn that goddamn thing off.
- 亞歷克斯
- 朋友們
- Alex.
- Guys.
是，對不起，市長
Yes, sir. Sorry, Your Honour.
發生了什麼，沃夫？路克•萊特又是怎麼卷進來的？
What's going on, Wolf?
And how's Luke Wright involved in it?
我本來也想問你這個問題
I figured I might ask you
the same question.
別和我玩游戲
Don't try to game me.
你不過就是個馬前卒
You're nothing but a pawn
下著一盤你無法掌控的大棋
playing on a board so big
you can't even see the edge.
僅此而已
That's all you've ever been.
直到5分鍾前我都比你更了解路克•萊特
I knew about Luke Wright, which is more
than you can say until five minutes ago.
你所知的路克•萊特
What you know about Luke Wright
還不到浩瀚資料中的一小片段
rates less than a paragraph
in a very fat book.
世貿大廈倒下後
After the towers fell
我們的人都分散出去追尋恐怖活動
and our manpower was spread out
tracking terrorist activity,
是我組織了特勤隊
I was the one
who formed the special task force
懲治犯罪以填補缺口
to deal with the crime
that was filling the gap.
別忘了也是我讓你來管理這支隊伍
And don't you ever fucking forget that
I was the one who put you in charge.
我從來沒忘記…我的工作成就了你的市長
I didn't forget. My work made you mayor.
你的工作？
Your work?
你以為路克只是你警察中的一員？
You think Luke
was just one of your cops?
當我拉起隊伍時，我知道它需要一面刀鋒
When I put together your team,
I knew it needed an edge
普通警探無法勝任，得像手術刀刀鋒一般
no ordinary detectives could give me,
something surgical.
我拜托那些甚至不存在於官方記錄中的朋友
I called friends in places buried
so deep they don't officially exist.
他們很同情我，一周後他們送來了路克•萊特
They were sympathetic.
A week later they sent Luke Wright.
那些過去七年裡消失的自作聰明的家伙
Those wise guys who vanished
over the last seven years,
你以為他們死於自相殘殺？
you think that was internecine war?
你在哈林區排水溝裡找到的可卡因
Those coke kings
you found in the gutter in Harlem.
布魯克林的弗雷迪•彼得羅維奇，中國城的湯米•勞
Freddy Petrovich in Brooklyn.
Tommy Lau in Chinatown.
路克•萊特是個幽靈
Luke Wright is a ghost.
非常致命的幽靈
A very deadly ghost.
而且工作很效率
It worked like a charm too.
然後你們這幫混蛋就忙著撈錢了
Then you dicks had to get greedy
and pad your pockets.
路克是個殺手，但是個誠實的殺手
Luke's a killer, but he's an honest one.
當他威脅說要把向情報局告發一切時
When he threatened to take
the whole thing to IA,
當時確實費了很大的勁
it took some people with a lot of bronze
stuck to their pyjamas
才搞定他
to talk him off the ledge.
如果我的隊伍解散，我們就又變回苦力了
Yeah, my team gets dismantled.
We're peons again.
但是如果路克•萊特有這麼深背景
But if Luke Wright's so connected,
為什麼他會淪落到在澤西打拳擊
how does he wind up in Jersey
cage fighting on the B circuit?
我看起來像心理醫生嗎？
Do I look like a shrink?
動員起所有人來
Get everybody on this.
一旦路克•萊特有了目標
Once Luke Wright gets on a roll,
整個城市只有一個人能在
一對一中和他抗衡
only one man in this city
can take him on one-on-one.
打擾了,我知道我不該打擾你們
I know this is a closed door,
但是市中心一座酒店發生了大規模槍戰
but there was just a major gun battle
downtown at a hotel.
媒體都瘋了,您需要趕緊做一份聲明
Media's going nuts.
You're gonna need to make a statement.
韓礁現在也在城裡
Han Jiao is in the city also.
他給了那個中國女孩一些東西,我不知道的東西
He give this little Chinese girl
something, I don't know what.
路克•萊特在我之前帶走了她
Luke Wright grabbed her before I could.
- 什麼？
- 我說路克•萊特
- What?
- I said Luke Wright...
知道了，我一開始就聽到了
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard you the first time.
關閉曼哈頓的每一個出口
Close every exit out of Manattan.
確保萊特和那個女孩逃不出去
Make sure that neither Wright or the
girl gets away, you get commissioner.
放跑了...你就找把鏟子自掘墳墓吧
Let 'em go... you get a shovel
to dig your own grave.
那個女孩絕不能離開這個城市
That girl does not leave this city.
誰殺了那個俄國人?
我不知道,他沒有告訴我
他有沒有問到那個數字？
每個人都問那個數字
那你跟他們講些什麼呢？
我什麼都沒說
什麼？
你在撒謊！！！
韓叔叔我當然不會給你撒謊的
打個電話告訴他們把阿梅的媽媽干掉
因為她的女兒是騙子
韓叔叔，我發誓，我假裝不會說英文也聽不懂
他們又吼又叫的但是我什麼都沒說，因為我知道你會生氣的
我向我媽發誓
我們找到了女孩，但是信息可能已經被洩漏
We recovered the girl, but the
information might have been compromised.
- 我們要改下時間表嗎？
- 不可能
- Should we change our time frame?
- lmpossible.
現在整件事情已經失控了
Now that the whole damn thing
has gone supernova,
今晚一定要了結此事
it's going to happen
and it's gonna happen tonight.
會面地點要改下
But the meeting place
needs to be changed.
- 到哪？
- 我會告訴你的
- Where to?
- I'll let you know.
這裡！就這裡！
Here. Right here.
慢點，停車
Slow down. Stop the car.
不行，不行，別把妓女帶上我的車子
No, no, you don't bring
no hookers in my cab, man.
繼續打你的表
Just keep the meter running.
小姐們
Ladies.
去喝一杯如何？
How about a drink?
晚上好
Good evening.
- 晚上好
- 想在這裡吃晚餐嗎？
- Evening.
- Will you be joining us for dinner?
- 我們沒有預定
- 沒事的
- We don't have a reservation.
- That's OK.
今晚雖然很忙，但是我們應該能給你們找到位置
We're busy tonight, but we should
be able to find you something.
樓下已經沒有空位了，不過背後還有些
We don't have any tables downstairs,
but there are some in the back.
或者如果你們喜歡的話，去樓上也可以
Or you could sit upstairs if you like.
先生？您怎麼看？先生？
Sir? Sir?
Do you have a preference? Sir?
我們就在吧台喝點酒
I think we'll just get a drink
at the bar.
你親我一下然後轉身出去
I want you to give me a kiss,
turn round and walk out of here.
- 但是我以為
- 就像你忘記了什麼東西一樣
- But I thought...
- Just act like you forgot something.
只是不要再回來了
Only don't come back.
來杯白俄羅斯，還有把叉子
Give me a white Russian, please,
and a fork.
- 叉子？
- 就那樣的
- Fork?
- One of those.
我從來不知這種時候該說什麼
什麼時候？
在我殺人之前
他開的什麼車？停在哪？
What does he drive
and where is it parked?
外面小路上的一輛銀色的SUV
A silver SUV in the alley outside.
- 瓦西裡
- 打錯了
- Vassily.
- Not even close.
你是誰？
Who is this?
整晚都在屠戮你手下的人，埃米爾
The guy who's been
killing your boys all night, Emile.
你的兒子在我手裡
The guy who has your son tied up
in a very dark place.
聽好，我想要…
Now, here's what I want.
你以為我會關心你想要什麼？
You think I give a shit
of what you want?
你以為抓了瓦西裡就能敲詐我？
Do you think you can blackmail me
because you have Vassily?
- 殺了他，下地獄去吧
- 我會下地獄的
- Kill him and go to hell.
- I'm going to hell all right.
不過我不會殺了你兒子
But I'm not gonna kill your boy.
我會把他帶在身邊，就像寵物一樣
I'm gonna keep him around, like a pet.
我對待寵物可不友善
A very badly treated pet.
我會做一些讓我以後每次照鏡子
I'm gonna do things to him
that'll make me ashamed
都覺得屈辱的事情，但是我會這麼做的
to look in the mirror afterward,
but I will do them.
瓦西裡會告訴我所有他所知道的
Vassily's gonna tell me everything
he knows about your operation.
然後你准備怎麼做？報警？
And then what you gonna do?
Tell the police?
- 你在搞笑嗎？
- 我之前有提到過警察嗎？
- You want me to laugh?
- Who said anything about the police?
我會把這些信息與你的競爭對手分享
I'm gonna share the information
with the competition,
我還沒干掉的那些家伙
the ones I haven't already killed.
我會拿光你所有的東西
Anything they don't take from you,
I will.
首先我會帶走你漂亮的老婆
First I'm gonna take your trophy wife.
然後是你的孩子們
Then I'm gonna take
your trophy children.
我會讓你一無所有
I'm gonna leave you with nothing.
當我完事後，你就什麼都不是了
When I'm done, you won't even be
a memory of a memory.
- 不過這些都沒必要發生
- 你想要什麼？
- But that doesn't have to happen.
- What do you want?
- 我想知道保險箱裡有什麼
- 什麼保險箱？
- I wanna know what's in the safe.
- What safe?
那個女孩給我密碼的那個保險箱
The safe the girl gave me
the combination to. That safe.
三千萬美元
$30 million.
那孩子本來要去拿第二個密碼，第二個保險箱裡有什麼？
Kid was on her way to get a second
number. What's in the second safe?
值三千萬美元的東西
Something won'th $30 million.
- 給誰？
- 不知道
- To who?
- No idea.
那是因為你只有小聰明，埃米爾
That's 'cause
you're only half-smart, Emile.
那麼，我們這麼說定了…
So here's the deal.
你告訴我第一個保險箱在哪，我拿了錢就放你兒子
You tell me where the first safe is,
I take the money and let your boy go.
騙我的話你就死定了，說到做到
Lie to me and yourworld ends.
You have my word on that.
白癡！我知道一個人是否獨行
Idiot. I know
when a man is working alone
而你正好只身一人
and you're as alone as one can be.
你需要一支隊伍才能靠近保險箱
You need a small army
to get near that safe,
我有這種隊伍
the kind of army I have.
曾經有過！我時間不多
Had. It's been shrinking by the minute.
最後一次機會，否則我就掛電話修理你兒子了
Last chance before I hang up
and go to work on your son.
你要殺我嗎，收垃圾的？
Going to kill me, garbage man?
你那天就可以把我們都干掉的，是嗎？
You could have taken us out that day,
couldn't you?
但是你只是跪在那裡
But you just sat there,
讓我們毀掉你，讓你變得一無是處
let us ruin you,
let us make you nothing.
我猜是保險箱給了你新的動力，是嗎，收垃圾的？
I guess finding out about that safe gave
you new motivation, eh garbage man?
如果我是你就不會浪費口舌
I wouldn't spend my time talking
if I were you.
會祈禱事情結束時，那小女孩還活著
Spend it praying that when this is over
that little girl's still alive.
祈禱！
Pray.
時間地點？
When and where?
橋下的地下道，一小時後
The underpass under the bridge,
one hour.
對不起，那些俄國人出現時我用槍指著你
I'm sorry I pointed a gun at you
when the Russians attacked us, Mei.
- 那只是…
- 生意而已…我知道的
- It was...
- Business. I know.
很好，很好，你理解
It's good. It's good you understand.
我們會搞定這一切
We're going to get this done
然後你跟我和韓叔一起就安全了
and you'll be safe
with me and Uncle Han.
我保證做一個好父親
I promise to be a better father to you
比那個拋棄你和你母親的家伙更好
than the one
who left you and your mother.
這個世界上沒人比我更關心你
There's no one in the world
who cares more about you.
你知道的，是嗎？
You know that, don't you?
人都到了
Well, the gang's all here.
差不多
Almost.
- 伯尼生病了？
- 他在醫院，混蛋！
- Reddick have to call in sick?
- He's in the hospital, dickhead.
- 你打壞了他的氣管
- 我從來不知道氣管還能被打壞
- You broke his trachea.
- I didn't know a trachea could break.
- 希望他們能修好
- 是嗎！不如讓我先修理你？
- Hope they can fix it.
- Yeah? How about I fix you?
嘿！嘿！嘿！嘿！別這樣！
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Not here.
好久不見，路克，不過我並不想念你
It's been a while, Luke.
Can't say I missed you.
- 那麼，有話直說吧
- 帶了我要的東西沒？
- So, let's get down to business.
- Did you bring what I asked for?
- 托斯卡尼的
- 還有呢？
- Toscanni's.
- Where else?
味道不錯！
Mmm. That's good.
我整晚都在餐館裡
Been in restaurants all night.
但是他們提供給我的都是子彈
All I got served was lead.
- 有火嗎？
- 去你的！
- Anyone got a light?
- You know what? Screw this.
聽著，隊長，你讓我們過來，我們過來了
Look, Captain, you asked us
to come here, so we came.
但我不會站在這裡聽這混蛋胡扯
But I ain't gonna sit here
and listen to this scumbag's big mouth.
閉嘴，科夫克斯！
Shut up, Kolfax.
還沒戒煙，哈？
Still haven't quit, huh?
嘿，嘿，這是什麼？
Hey. Hey, what the hell is that?
裝有三千萬美元保險箱的密碼
Combination of the safe
with 30 million bucks in it.
- 哇，哇！你在干嘛？
- 你個狗屎
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Filthy piece of shit.
現在這密碼存在我腦子裡了
The only place it exists now is in here.
當你們手癢想扣扳機時，記住這點
Remember that next time
your little triggerfinger gets itchy.
為什麼韓礁會把它藏在
Why would Han Jiou stash it
中國城最繁忙的賭窩裡？
right in the middle of Chinatowrs
busiest gambling den?
因為伯努瓦這樣的喜歡
Because of sleaze-bucket cops
like you, Benoit,
去賭窩收保護費腐敗警察
who collect off of Chinatowrs
busiest gambling den.
想不吸引警察的注意
Where else would he surround it
with dozens of armed man
他還能放在哪裡？
without attracting police attention?
隊長,我們怎麼知道這混蛋不是在玩我們？他是個流浪漢！
Captain, why do we know this son of
a bitch on the level, huh? He's a bum.
你從哪得到的消息？
Where'd you get your information?
今晚會有個交易
There's an exchange happening tonight.
三合會半數交易額都在賭場保險箱裡
The Triad half of the deal
is in a safe in the casino.
我一人搞不定，所以我叫了你們，老朋友們
No way I could get to it on my own,
so I called on you, my old pals.
三千萬美元分六份依然是很大一筆錢
30 million split six ways
is still a lot of money.
我們風險太大，隊長，尤其是你
We're risking a lot, Captain.
You especially.
所有人都知道你前途光明
Everybody knows you got a bright future.
誰保證的？你的市長？
Promised by who? His Honour?
他跟你承諾什麼了，沃夫？
What carrot
is he teasing you with, Wolf?
若他知道你所掌握的，他還會放過你？
He's gonna let you out in the street
knowing what you know now?
你什麼意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是，他的第二任期快到頭了，什麼保證都是屁
His second term is gonna come to an end
and his hold on the city goes poof.
就跟普通公民一樣
Just like that he's Joe Citizen again.
三千萬是一筆不錯的退休金
30 million would be
a nice retirement package.
他給中國佬什麼好處？
What's he giving the Chinks?
如果我知道，還會跟你們這幫混蛋站在這裡？
If I knew that, I wouldn't be standing
here with you assholes, would I?
光明未來，哈？
A bright future, huh?
頭條
Big headlines.
“英雄警察破獲紐約最大的地下賭博巢穴”
"Hero cops take down New York City's
biggest underground gambling operation."
每人五百萬美元，且沒人知道
Five million bucks apiece
that no one will ever know about,
就當是額外甜頭
just to give it that extra sweet taste.
好了，誰進去過？拜托，誰進去過？
All right, who's been in there?
For Christ's sake, who's been in there?
- 我，隊長
- 你倆做先鋒
- Me, Cap.
- You two, you're on point.
裡面都是平民，看准了打
Place is packed with civilians,
so exercise some judgement.
記住只有我有密碼
Remember, I got the combination.
如果你們想要錢，掩護好我
You want that money, watch my back.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
別動！待著！
Don't move! Stay!
讓開！走！
Out of the way! Move!
嘿，你，去死吧！
Hey, you, settle down!
這裡！走！
This way. Let's go.
小心
Heads up.
走
Go.
科夫克斯，干掉他
Kolfax, take him out.
掩護他
Cover him.
打開它，開槍！
Open it. Take it!
靠！
Oh, shit!
靠！我必須離開這裡
Oh, shit.
I gotta get out of here.
操，操，隊長
Oh, fuck. Fuck, Captain.
天啊，你個混蛋！你殺了同伴，你個混蛋！
God, you shit!
Shoot a man in the back, son of a bitch!
- 好了，米爾斯，我們往哪走？
- 這裡
- All right, Mears, where we going?
- This way.
快
Move.
我們被襲擊了
他們不是俄國人，好像是警察
不過他們比警察更厲害
派點人來，他們殺了很多人，快點啊，我們需要...
告訴張，盡快拿到那個數字然後把跑腿的干掉
這個數字由我們自己來破解
你們聽懂了嗎？
- 天堂之門到了
- 把我們這樣的罪人拒之門外
- The gates of paradise.
- Locked and bolted to sinners like us.
好了，別浪費時間
Yeah, well,
let's not wait for an invitation.
好了，你個混蛋，快點開始
All right, you bastard. Get started.
下面按我說的做
Here's how we do this.
你們先放下槍，我再開保險箱
You put down your guns, I open the safe.
如果你們想殺我，隨意
If you wanna shoot me, go ahead.
快點決定，真警察馬上就要到了
Make your minds up quick
'cause the real cops'll be here soon.
放到地上
On the floor.
快點，你個混蛋，你想干什麼？
Come on, you son of a bitch.
What are you trying to pull?
密碼左右方向反了，馬上就開了
I had right left switched.
It's gonna open.
你會活著的
You'll live.
左26
Left 26.
沃夫隊長，這裡發生了什麼？
Captain Wolf,
what the hell happened in here?
你以為發生了什麼，哈？我們突襲了這裡
What do you think happened, huh?
We had a raid on the place go bad.
有人員傷亡，趕緊給我進去處理
We got dead cops, casualties.
Get in there, will you?
- 沃夫隊長，你需要救護車
- 我需要一排救護車
- Captain Wolf, you need an ambulance.
- I need a fleet of ambulances.
趕緊叫救護車，懂嗎？我自己開去醫院
Call it in, will you? I'll take
my own busted ass to the hospital.
演技不錯
Not bad.
如果你不是個兩面派，我幾乎都喜歡上你了
If you werert such a double-dealing
asshole, I could almost like you.
是幾乎！開車！
Almost. Drive.
只是劃傷
It's a scratch.
我不會殺你，但我可沒說讓你住大酒店
I'm not gonna kill you, but I didn't say
I was putting you up at the Ritz.
沃夫
Wolf.
我需要錢，丹尼
I have your money, Danny.
什麼？
What?
你聽見了
You heard me.
三千萬！五千份一千美元的支票
30 million. Five-thousand
and one-thousand dollar bills.
- 我想談談
- 不行
- I wanna talk.
- No.
你需要的是冷靜下來我們好談點正常的
No, what you wanna do is calm down
so we can talk like adults.
閉嘴，丹尼
Shut it, Danny.
我是想談，不過不是和你談
I wanna talk,
but I don't wanna talk to you.
我要和你男朋友談
I wanna talk to your boyfriend.
我是亞歷克斯
This is Alex.
好久不見，亞歷克斯
Been a while, Alex.
- 你怎麼拿到這號碼的？
- 別這樣，亞歷克斯
- How'd you get this number?
- Come on, Alex.
順著市長的味就能找到你
Reach up the mayor's ass, there you are.
男人就該有男人樣，哈？
A mars gotta do
what a mars gotta do, huh?
他總比安妮這誘餌好
He's a better catch
than Annie was anyway.
我一直不解你為什麼會勾搭上那樣一頭奶牛
I never understood
how you hooked up with a cow like that.
絕不是因為她的長相，而是她的幽默感
It was never about her looks.
It was her sense of humour.
她現在沒那麼搞笑了，不是麼？
She's not so funny now, is she?
不是了，我也一樣
No, she's not. Neither am I.
我拿到了錢，亞歷克斯，我殺了很多人才弄到的
I have the money, Alex.
I had to kill a lot of people to get it.
所以聽著
So listen up.
你還沒交換過密碼，另一個保險箱裡是什麼？
You haven't made the combination
exchange yet. What's in the other safe?
一張碟片
A disc.
名字，錢的來龍去脈…
Names, money trails.
當指揮官派我們幫丹尼清理城市時
When our commanders sent the two of us
to help Danny clean up the city,
他們附加了一個條件
they attached a price.
作為交換，丹尼要自尋財路
In exchange, Danny looked the other way
而每筆被當做恐怖組織查抄的集團資金
while the assets seized from every group
deemed a terrorist organisation
則裝進了他們的私人腰包
were funnelled
into their private accounts.
驚訝是他們受驚需要保護時
Amazing what people
let you get away with
卻把你趕走了
when they're scared
and wanna feel protected.
驚訝的是有那麼多小人
Amazing how many scumbags
there are out there
都等著乘機牟利
waiting to take advantage of it.
- 難道你沒有麼？
- 我退出了
- Like you didn't?
- I quit.
你以為這能幫那些被你私自送去見上帝的人
Bet that helps all those souls you sent
to meet their maker without due process
省下很多功夫嗎？
rest a whole lot easier.
你以為你在拳擊場上
You thought you could atone
by climbing into a cage
被人隨意毆打就能贖罪嗎？
and allowing yourself
to get beaten to a pulp?
別給我說教了，路克！
Don't fucking preach at me, Luke.
我只是收錢辦事
I'm getting paid for services rendered.
是啊，你把碟片賣給中國人好讓他們勒索我們上司
Right. You sell the disc to the Chinese
so they can blackmail our old honchos,
然後拿著三千萬美元和丹尼去巴哈馬別墅逍遙自在
take the 30 mill and waltz off
with Danny to a villa in the Bahamas.
是巴厘島，不過無所謂了，不是麼？
Bali, but whatever, right?
那麼，就算你知道了，又如何？
So, now you know. Now what?
現在你要應付我
Now you're dealing with me.
- 好吧，我退出
- 不行
- All right, I'm turning around.
- No, you're not.
你說什麼？你已經拿到錢了
What are you talking about?
You've got the money.
- 中國人手裡沒有我要的了
- 不，他們有我想要的
- The Chinese have nothing I care about.
- No. They have something I do.
把你保險箱密碼給這女孩，她會給你我們的
Give the girl the combination to your
safe and she will give you our number.
我們到你的地方，你去我們的
We go to your location, you go to ours.
當我們拿到碟片，我們會給你解密密碼
When we've gotten the disc,
we will explain the code
你拿到你的錢
and you'll get the cash.
一言為定
That's the deal.
- 說說看吧
- 這是個很長的數字
- Let's hear it.
- It's a very long number.
你最好能記下來
You'll want to write it down.
感謝上帝我還帶了筆，哈？
Thank goodness I brought a pen, huh?
你最好閉上眼睛
You might wanna close your eyes.
隨你便吧
Have it your way.
快接，路克
Come on, Luke.
老地方，就你和我
The old place, just you and me.
你是路克的朋友嗎？
You're a friend of Luke?
這不是你該關心的
Not as far as you're concerned.
今晚席卷整個紐約的暴力活動
The violence
that has rocked the city tonight
依舊持續，不到一小時前
continued in a bloody gun battle
中國城一家夜總會爆發了血腥槍戰
in a Chinatown nightclub
less than an hourago.
- 這已經完全失控了
- 你以為呢？
- This is really getting out of hand.
- You think?
謝謝提醒
Thanks for that insight.
市長，亞歷克斯•羅瑟斯在你私人專線上
Your Honour,
Alex Rosers on your private line.
他說有急事
He says that it's urgent.
- 打擾一下，市長
- 我5分鍾後回來，現在別煩我
- Excuse me, Your Honour.
- Back in five. Don't bother me now.
他為什麼不打我手機？
Why didn't he call me on my cellphone?
我記得讓你把所有電話都接到我的…
I thought I told you to put
all my calls through to the...
我一直跟你說這裡保安水平太差
I always told you this place
had lousy security standards.
那是因為沒人會瘋到像你一樣來這殺人
Because nobody's been crazy enough to
come in here and pull a stunt like this.
- 你有種，路克
- 是啊，真是驚訝我還能走路
- You got some balls, Luke.
- Yeah, amazing I can even walk.
給我碟片
The disc.
什麼？你以為我會傻到讓中國幫派
What, you think I'm stupid enough
to let a gang of Chinese
穿過前門進到房間來拿它？
walk up the front steps and collect it
from me in my living room?
- 它在離這很遠的保險箱裡
- 我不認為你很蠢
- It's in a safe far away from here.
- I don't think you're stupid.
所以我不認為你只有一份拷貝
Which is why I don't for a second
believe you gave away the only copy.
我會去見亞歷克斯
I'm going to meet Alex.
你先給我碟片，不然我就在非要害的部位給你一槍
First you give me the disc or I'll put
bullets in places that won't kill you
讓你下半輩子生不如死
but make you spend
the rest of your life wishing I had.
滿意了?
Satisfied?
我要確認一下這不是“金剛葫蘆娃”
I wanna make sure
it's not ABBA'sGreatest Hits.
亞歷克斯會殺了你的,你知道的
Alex will kill you, you know.
嗯，或許吧
Yeah, probably.
上帝，路克，你氣色很不好
Jesus. Luke, you look like hell.
酒精而已，缺少睡眠和陽光
Just alcohol, lack of sunlight,
sleep deprivation.
除此以外，我感覺不錯
Other than that, I feel great.
呵，我在想，我們在這裡拋過多少屍了？
You know, I was thinking, how many
bodies have we dumped in this place?
你知道的，我從不記數
You know, I didn't keep count.
他們都是混蛋，不是麼？
They were all assholes, though, right?
放開她，亞歷克斯
Let her go, Alex.
丹尼打電話說你去拜訪過他
Danny called.
He told me about your visit.
我不得不承認，我都沒想到這一手
I have to admit,
even I didn't see that one coming.
你現在有了錢和碟片
You had the disc and the money.
什麼...
What...
她對你來說意味著什麼？
What is she to you?
生命
Life.
好吧，趁還有命就好好享受吧
Well, enjoy it while it lasts,
不久她就會讓你的小命玩完的
'cause she's the reason
yours is gonna be a whole lot shorter.
錢在哪，路克
The money, Luke.
在車裡
In the car.
或者銀行裡
Or in the bank.
或者在中央車站儲物櫃裡
Or in a series of lockers
at Grand Central.
或者我可能出於好心悉數捐出了
Or maybe I donated it to charity,
out of the goodness of my heart.
想要知道下落，你就得來硬的
You wanna find out where that money is,
you're gonna have to do it the hard way.
你還好吧，梅？
You all right, Mei?
我見過他打斗，你打不過他的
I saw him fight before.
Bad business for you.
是啊，最糟的是
Yeah. The worst.
你又救了我
You saved me, again.
我們救了對方
We save each other.
我知道你在想什麼
I know how you feel.
幫我把這垃圾弄出來
Help me get this sack of garbage
out of the car.
確保他安全回到他老爸那兒
Make sure he gets to his daddy
safe and sound.
5萬，賠償你的損失
50 grand, for your trouble.
錢可能不多，但至少你有命花
Might not seem like much, but at least
you're gonna live to enjoy it.
在經歷了這麼多後，你還想放過他？
You want him safe and sound
after what he did to you?
為了她
For her sake.
若再見面，你就萬事皆休
We meet again, all bets are off.
最尊敬的叔叔
這裡有兩千九百九十五萬美元
我們會還余下的5萬，再加10%的利息
如果萬一您還生氣
我必須告訴您，我知道您在中國城生意的每一個帳號
還有匯錢到中國的途徑
您不找我們的麻煩，我們也不會找您的麻煩
來追我們的話，你的世界就完了
我保證說話算話
給我准備飛機票
我再也不想看到這個
鬼地方！
- 你媽的給我看路，哥們！
- 走你的
- Watch where you're fucking going, man!
- Keep walking.
- 什麼？再說一遍？啥？
- 走開
- Excuse me? Pardon me? Anything?
- Walk.
這是他媽的紐約！
This is fucking New York City!
- 第五家銀行了，還有幾家？
- 沒了
- Bank number five. How many more?
- That's it.
現在碟片拷貝已遍布城市保險櫃
Got copies of the disc
in security boxes all over the city.
如果我們出事
Anything happens to us,
很多大人物就得倒霉
a lot of important people
are gonna be very sorry.
我們的護身符，這是筆好生意
Our security. Good business for us.
- 現在干嘛？
- 我們離開這裡
- What now?
- Now we get out of town.
梅，你是個孩子…我不確定自己能否做個好父親
Mei, you're a kid and...
I'm not sure I could be a good father.
我想我能力不足
I think that ship has sailed.
我不想要父親
I don't want no more fathers.
你可以做我朋友嗎？
Will you be my friend?
至死都願
Till my dying day.
我找到一家在西雅圖專門培訓天才兒童的學校
I got info on a school
for gifted kids up in Seattle.
這會是次美妙旅行，如果你喜歡那裡的風光的話
It's a nice drive,
if you like trees and shit.
我們安全了嗎？
Are we safe?
別想太多，梅，別想太多
One day at a time, Mei.
One day at a time.
=-全片完，謝謝觀賞-=
更多精彩影視，盡在HDCHINA.ORG